Result-oriented associate-level network security professional and a recent graduate, with experience in network troubleshooting, deploying network devices, maintaining connectivity and **4 years customer support** experience. **Dedicated, self-motivated** individual who is flexible for working hours, capable in handling multiple tasks and committed to meet deadlines while working either individually or as an active team member.

Technical Proficiency

- Installation, Configuration and Troubleshooting: Routers, Switches (L2 & L3), Firewalls, Access Points, Wireless Controllers
- Operating Systems: Cisco IOS, Windows 10, Linux, MacOS
- Network Fundamentals: TCP/IP, VOIP, DNS, DHCP, IPv4, IPv6, CIDR
- WAN Connectivity: MPLS, Point-to-Point, Point-to-Multipoint, VPN
- Routing Protocols: (Static, RIP, OSPF & EIGRP) for IPv4 and IPv6
- LAN switching: STP, RSTP, VLAN, VTP, Ether Channel (L2 & L3)
- Network Security: Authentication, TACACS+, RADIUS, ACLs, NAT/PAT, VPN, IPSEC, SSL
- Network Monitoring and Troubleshooting: SSH, SNMPv3, Syslog, Wireshark, PRTG
- MS office 2016 (Visio, Project, Word, Power point, Excel)
- Network Infrastructure: Microsoft Server 2012,2016
- Intermediate knowledge of AD DS, Clustering, Groups, GPO, OUs, Replication Strategies

Education & Credentials

Postgraduate Diploma in Wireless Information Networking

2018 - 2020

Conestoga College, Kitchener, ON

Bachelor of Technology (Electronics and communication)

2012 - 2016

I.K.G. - Punjab Technical University, Punjab, India

Certifications

- CCNA Routing and Switching (2021)
- Aure 900
- CCNP Enterprise (In Progress)

Experience

Network Support Analyst

Feb 2016 – Aug 2017

INTELENET GLOBAL SERVICES, Mohali, India

Provided first level first level database monitoring and network incident support to call center employees.

- **Common Troubleshooting:** Fixed common hardware and software issues on advisor's desktop systems and communicated the incident over mail for documentation and event tracking.
- Citrix Support: Configured and resolved Citrix receiver remote PC access and user management.
- Escalations and Follow-ups: Raised escalation tickets with NICE and Novel-Vox backend teams for special issues.
- Prepared reference for users by writing operating instructions.
- Maintained historical records by documenting hardware and software changes and revisions.

Shift Manager

McDonald's Kitchener, Canada

Nov 2017 - Present

- Taking the lead role in running the entirety of a station or area, as well as the entire store
- Ensuring Operational targets of Ownership/Corporate are met on a consistent basis
- Motivate, encourage and assist team mates to enhance performance/morale.
- Scheduling, Inventory, Food Cost control Crew Development
- Providing outstanding customer service to each Guest